Guide to the Scholars of the House Program, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Scholars of the House Program, Yale University, records
1950-1987
RU 143
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
42
The records consist of correspondence, reports, proposals, student essays and projects, and student files documenting the Yale Scholars of the House Program.
Yale College (1887- )
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-E (YRG 9-E), Records documenting Yale College offices, programs, and projects.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, reports, proposals, student essays and projects, and student files documenting the Yale Scholars of the House Program.
Independent study; Talented students; Universities and colleges -- Honors courses; Essays; Yale College (1887- ); Yale University -- Students
- Student essays and projects, circa 1950-1974; Accession 19ND-A-382
  Conditions Governing Access
  Requires written permission of the author or copyright holder to copy.
  - Aznoff, E.S.: England, the United States and the Trent Affair, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Adamson, D.: The Queen Bird and Others, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Alpert, J.: The Influence of Environmental Oxygen on the Ecology and Development of the Paradise Fish, Macropodus Opercularis, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Allison, H.E.: Freedom and Failure, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Arditi, A.: The Word as Icon: A Study in the Philosophy of Literature, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Aspin, L., Jr.: The Personnel and Policies of the Country Party in the House of Commons, 1679, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, N.L.: Scholar of the House Project, Parts I and II, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Aronson, S.M.L.: Brown Betty, 1965 (Box 2)
    Restricted: author must give written permission to read.
  - Asthalter, R.: 1786-1788: Philosophy, Politics, and the Formation of the American Constitution, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Astrachan, A.M.: Myth as an Historical Force, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Avlon, J.J.: The Peninsular Precedents, Establishment, and Regulation of Hapsburg Peruvian Government, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Berger, Charles William: Symbolism and Romantic Poetry, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Bell, Willis: Grand Illusion, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Bagnall, Roger S., III: Attica and the Greek Mainland in the Dark Age, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Bai, Arnold: A History of the Movement for Indian National Liberation, vols. I and II, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Bildner, Robert: Strategies and Effects of Multinational Corporations in Iran and Yugoslavia, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Best, Geoffrey: Shall Our Blood Fail?, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Beshar, R.P.: The Consciousness of Freedom, 1950 (Box 4)
  - Bergman, Peter P.: "One Big Industrial Union", 1961 (Box 4)
  - Bakker, Robert T.: Pectoral Biomechanics and Tetrapod Evolution, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Bush, Robert L.: The British Labour Left and U.S. Foreign Policy, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Bialek, R.W.: Church and State in Ecuador, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Bicknell, Kent L.: The Ascent to God, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Barnett, Jonathan: Expressive Content in Architecture, vols. 1, 2, 3, 4, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Bogardus, Edgar C.: Stories and Poems, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Blonsky, Marshall St.: The World of Marvell's Poetry, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Blanpied, John W.: Speeches at Dark, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Biller, Alan D.: Psychoanalysis and Explanation, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Bickwitt, L. Jr.: Seeds for Chaos, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Blum, Jake and Wilhelm, John: "Vito Marcantonio": the Politics of Dissent, 2 vols., 1967 (Box 7)
  - Bush, Robert B.: Summary of Painting, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Bildner, Robert: Strategies and Effects of Multinational Corporations in Iran and Yugoslavia, copy 2, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Borgzinner, John A.: Short Stories and Vignettes, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Bradley, Edmund L.: The Tradition of Individualism in American Politics, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Barasch, Alan Sidney: Zarathustra--The Recurrence of Tightrope-walking, 2 copies, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Bromwich, David L.: Ancestral Themes: Emerson and His Tradition, 2 copies, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Byard, Paul S.: The Sense Sublime, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Buchmann, Alan P.: Theriomorphic Vessels from the Ancient Near East and Crete, 1956 (Box 8)
  - Brown, William E., Jr.: The Theory and Structure of Religious Symbolism, 1956 (Box 8)
  - Bruck, Gerald Jr.: Gone with the James River and Kanawha Canal, vols. 1 and 2, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Cunningham, Clark E.: The Postwar Migration of the Toba-Batak to East Sumatra, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Chabner, Bruce A.: The Disposition of Palestine, 1919, 1961 (Box 10)
  - Celeste, Richard F.: Toward an African Personality, 1959 (Box 10)
  - Campbell, Duncan A. III: The Intellectual and Politics: Jean-Paul Sartre (1945-1952), 1966 (Box 10)
  - Cather, S. Robertson: A Project of Creative Writing, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Courtright, James B.: Developmental and Cytological Studies of a Sex-Linked Recessive Lethal in DROSUPHILIA MELANOGASTER, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Cohn, Stephen A.: Claude Simon: A Critical Examination, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Cope, Gerald P., Jr.: Insurgent Republicanism in Florida, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Conversi, Leonard: Forms in the Later Poetry of W. B. Yeats, 1952 (Box 11)
  - Congdon, William H.C.: Philosophy, Religion, and Man's Spiritual Reality, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Clevenger, Raymond C. III: The Berquin Affair, 1521-1523 materials used (separate folder), 1959 (Box 11)
  - Cooke, Michael G.: The Bastions of Innocence, 1957 (Box 12)
  - Chun-Hoon, Lowell K.Y.: The Anomalous and the Expected: Anson Burlingame and the Anti-Chinese Movement in the United States, 1848-1902, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Crocker, John L.: Analyticity, Necessity, a Priority, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Crunden, Robert M.: Albert Jay Nock, 1962 (Box 12)
  - Cowles, Frederick O.: The History of Moroccan Nationalism 1926-1956, 1959 (Box 12)
  - Davis, Robert: The Treatment of Ambition in Tudor Literature, 1971 (Box 13)
  - Dominquez, Virginia R.: The Middle Race, 2 copies, 1973 (Box 13)
  - de Ferranti, David M.: Ideas on the Role of the State in England During World War I, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Daly, Edwin: A Legacy of Love, 1958 (Box 14)
  - Dickinson, A.J.: Myth and Manipulation: the Story of the Crusade for Voters in Richman, Virginia, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Deutsch, Jan G.: Change and the Conservative: A Historical Biography of Prince Felix zu Schwarzenberg vols. I and II, 1955 (Box 14)
  - De Neufville, John: Stratigraphy, Batholith Emplacement, and Contact Metasomatism at Cerro Tierra Amarilla, near Copiapo, Atacama Province, Chile, 1961 (Box 14)
  - Duke, Daniel L.: Origins of the One-Party State in Uganda: A Historical Analysis of Structural Authority in a Transitional Society, vols. I and II, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Donovan, F.: Cesare Pavese "essay and translation", 1963 (Box 15)
  - Duncan, H.E. Anthony: Inverse Scattering Theory and Doubled Resonances, undated (Box 15)
  - Dominguez, Jorge I.: The Foreign Policy of the Cuban Revolution, vols. I, II, III, IV, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Ewell, Peter: The Image of Man in High Gothic Sculpture, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Ellsworth, Thomas B., Jr.: The Stars and Stripes at Sea: A Study of the Development of Federal Maritime Policy since 1860, 1961 (Box 16)
  - Eisengart, Marvin A.: The House of Prayer, 1962 (Box 16)
  - Evans, David R.: The Christ-Figure in Dostoevsky and Faulkner, 1955 (Box 17)
  - Epstein, Leslie: The Stage of Liberty, vols. 1 and 2, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Enders, Thomas O.: A Study of Personal Power and Political Change in Medieval Morocco: Ibn-Tumart to ash-Shaikh, 1953 (Box 17)
  - Elting, James J.: The Pattern of Entombment: A Study in the Works of Edgar Allen Poe, 1961 (Box 17)
  - Fetner, Philip J.: British and French Diplomacy towards the Schleswig-Holstein Crisis, 1860-1864, 1965 (Box 18)
  - Fayen, George S., Jr.: Faust--Myth and Milieu, vols., I and II, 1953 (Box 18)
  - Friedlander, Richard A.:... In the Way of Progress: a Study of the Homestead Steel Strike of 1892, undated (Box 19)
  - Fishman, Mark C.: Audiovisual Responses of Cells in the Visual Cortex, 1972 (Box 19)
  - Frede, Richard S.: Summer is for Getting Away and other stories, undated (Box 19)
  - Francis, John M.: Konstantin Leontiev (1831-1891), 1957 (Box 19)
  - Fischer, Richard A.: The Ocular Stance, 1966 (Box 19)
  - Griffin, James P.: Plato's Theory of Being, undated (Box 20)
  - Goldthwaite, John C.: Three Stories, a Novella, Poems, Three Fragments, Notes, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Gilbert, Bennett B.: On Metaphysical Questions and Metaphysical Answers, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Gibbons, Michael F., Jr.: The Phyletic Position of Oreopithecus, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Gardner, James N.: The Literary Mode in Kierkegaard and Sartre, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Gates, C.C.: Truth in Ruskin and the English Landscape Tradition, 1956 (Box 20)
  - Greenwald, Anthony G.: Patterns of Aggression and War, 1959 (Box 21)
  - Givan, Christopher F.: Everyone Watching, vols. I, II, III, IV, 1966 (Box 21)
  - Gustafson, Richard F.: Fedor Ivanovitch Tiutchev, undated (Box 22)
  - Griggs, Douglas M.: Businessman, Bureaucrat, or Professional: A Study of Occupational Choice among Negro College Students, 1964 (Box 22)
  - Gelmann, Edward P.: Studies of Control of the Unsaturated Fatty Acid Content of Bacterial Membranes, 1972 (Box 22)
  - Gates, Louis Skip: A Once and Future King, 1973 (Box 22)
  - Gulliver, Harold: Seven Stories, 2 copies, 1957 (Box 23)
  - Gubser, N.J.: The Nunamiut Eskimo: Hunters of Caribou, 1962 (Box 23)
  - Hartke, Stephen Paul: Passion, Poison, and Petrifaction, folio with notes, 1973 (Box 24)
  - Hatchett, John W.: A Physical Theory of the Origin of Life, 1972 (Box 24)
  - Henry, William A., III: The Restoration of Morality, 1971 (Box 24)
  - Healer, Michael: The Burning of the Magnum Wreath, undated (Box 24)
  - Harries, Karsten: Change and Permanence, 1958 (Box 24)
  - Hammond, Fred F.: Psalms and Hymns and Spiritual Songs, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Hobson, Bartholomew: Andrew Starnam's Literary Memoirs, 1970 (Box 25)
  - Harding, Peter M.: Biography of Augustus Earle, vols. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, (10, 11 shelved separately in Box 26A), 1964 (Box 26, Box 26A)
  - Hazel, Paul: Dominion, undated (Box 27)
  - Joralemon, Peter D.: A Study of Olmec Iconography, vols. I and II, 1969 (Box 28)
  - Jonas, Christopher: The Origins of Language, 1966 (Box 28)
  - Jones, Gerald: Six Stories, 1957 (Box 28)
  - Kaplanoff, Mark D.: From Colony to State: New Hampshire, 1800-1815, 1970 (Box 29)
  - Karshmer, Gary C.: The Don Juan of Literature: A New Criticism, undated (Box 29)
  - Kapuler, Alan M.: Intragenic Complementations, 1962 (Box 29)
  - Kahrl, William L.: The Profits of Disorder, 1968 (Box 29)
  - Kline, Edward: Mathematical Structure of Modern Physics, 1952 (Box 30)
  - Kelly, Edward F.: Creative Thinking and Creative Personality Structure, 1962 (Box 30)
  - Katz, Joel: Apparently untitled, vol. 1, vol. 2--photographs, undated (Box 30)
  - Kirs, Anton O.: The Effect of Small Anterior Cortical Lesions on Fear and Competition, 1955 (Box 31)
  - Kettl, Donald F.: The Midnight Special, 1974 (Box 31)
  - Koch, John S.: A Time to Dance, 1953 (Box 31)
  - Kutnick, Dale: The Mountains Go Up and Down, the Rivers Flow, vols. I and II, undated (Box 31)
  - Knowles, James B., Jr.: Sculpture Project, 1966 (Box 32)
  - Kyr, Robert H.: Audio Tapes of Voyage, undated (Box 32)
  - Lee, Alfred: My Striptease Girlfriend, and Toward Defining Poetry, 1960 (Box 33)
  - Langlois, Walter G., Jr.: Six Keys in Search of a Door, 1950 (Box 33)
  - Lamb, William P.: The World of Delight, 1960 (Box 33)
  - Lang, Bevel: Three Concepts of Time: Proust, Weizsacker, Whitehead, 1954 (Box 33)
  - Lamb, Karl: A Stranger within Him, 1954 (Box 33)
  - Lesser, Rika: Poems and Translations, 1974 (Box 34)
  - Lozowick, Arnold H.: The British Labor Movement, 1910-1914, 1951 (Box 34)
  - Light, Timothy: A Comic View, 1960 (Box 34)
  - Levy, Nelson L.: The Role of Protein Biosynthesis in the Breaking of Diapause in Crecopia Silkmoth Pupae, 1963 (Box 34)
  - Lemisch, L. Jesse: Franklin's Social Attitudes, 1957 (Box 34)
  - Luria, Nelson J.: Methodist Missionaries in China 1927-1930, 2 copies, 1963 (Box 35)
  - Lungstrom, John W.: Kansas's Progressive Republican: a Political Biography of Alf M. Landon, 1967 (Box 35)
  - Murphy, Timothy: Poems, 1972 (Box 36)
  - McNamee, C.T., III: Poems, Unsuccessful Attempts at Poems, Rock songs: lyrics, Rock songs: music, 1969 (Box 36)
  - Morson, Gary S.: Pushkin's Tales of Belkin, 1969 (Box 36)
  - Magowan, Stephen: Harlequinade, 1968 (Box 36)
  - Mallach, Alan: Aspects of Radical Politics in New York City, 1966 (Box 36)
  - Malmgren, Harold B.: Investment, Allocation, Technology, and Economic Development, 1957 (Box 36)
  - Maffitt, Peter C.: Colombia--the Revolution on the March, 1934-1938, 1963 (Box 36)
  - Makover, Richard B.: Psychology and Literary Criticism: An Evaluation, 1960 (Box 36)
  - Mattysse, Steven W.: Stability Properties of Cellular Biosynthesis, 1959 (Box 37)
  - Marshak, David: Eeeclipse, 1971 (Box 37)
  - Mathewson, Joseph: Four Plays, vols. 1 and 2, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Marriott, B. Rodney: The Escape to Reality, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Mamis, J.E.: Behold, This Dreamer Cometh, 1950 (Box 37)
  - Miller, Donald G., Jr.: Dostoevsky: A Study of Freedom and Faith, 1955 (Box 38)
  - Mesler, David P.: A Critique of the RSV New Testament, 1956 (Box 38)
  - Meyer, Russell W., Jr.: Procedural Reform of Congressional Investigations, 1954 (Box 38)
  - Mellon, Tim: The Peronist Movement in Argentine Politics, 1964 (Box 38)
  - Meilen, Gerhard: The Children of Strangers, undated (Box 38)
  - McLennan, William L., Jr.: Finite Man--Infinite Mind, 1971 (Box 38)
  - Mittenthal, Stephen D.: The Lost Cause of Loyalty, 1959 (Box 39)
  - Muller, Edward N.: After Teas, Cakes, and Icings, undated (Box 39)
  - Michelman, Frank I.: The Progressive Uses of Darwinism, 1957 (Box 39)
  - Marton, Kenneth L.: Modelling in the Neurosciences: A Study of the Vertebrate Retina, 2 copies, 1973 (Box 40)
  - More, John H., Jr.: A Re-examination of Senecan Tragedy, 1964 (Box 40)
  - Morcroft, Richard L.: Political Participation in Mexico, 1964 (Box 40)
  - Moore, Thomas R.: The Noble Historys of the Saynt Grayle, undated (Box 40)
  - Mills, Richard P.: The Flight Muscles of Drosophila Melanogaster, 1964 (Box 40)
  - Menefee, Samuel P.: Studies in Megalithic Folklore, 1972 (Box 41)
  - Masters, Donald J., Jr.: The New Frontier, the Special Forces, and Vietnam, 1972 (Box 41)
  - Newberger, Eli H.: The Major Jazz Piano Styles, 1962 (Box 42)
  - Nessen, Maurice N.: From Labor Representation Committee to Labor Party, 1950 (Box 42)
  - Nembhard, Alric B.: The Function of Folklore in Two National Institutions in Jamaica, 2 copies, 1973 (Box 42)
  - O'Conner, J.D.: A Study of the Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland, 1959 (Box 43)
  - Powerman, Charles: The Shadow God, 1966 (Box 44)
  - Posner, Richard: Yeat's Late Poetry, 1959 (Box 44)
  - Pearsall, Otis P.: An American Surveys the Integration of Western Europe, 1953 (Box 44)
  - Parsons, Peter: "Newe Heavens and Helles", undated [1960] (Box 44)
  - Purves, Dale: Freud and the Structure of Anxiety, 1960 (Box 45)
  - Quammen, David: Absalom, Absalom! a screenplay and direction, undated (Box 46)
  - Quint, David: Structure and Meaning in the Halian Carolingian Epic, 1971 (Box 46)
  - Renan, Sheldon: Eight Stories and a Novelette, 1963 (Box 47)
  - Reed, Mark L.: A Man Speaking to Men, 1957 (Box 47)
  - Rae, Thomas: The Tragedy of Misunderstanding, 1952 (Box 47)
  - Ravenscroft, Kent Jr.: Spirit Possession in Haiti: A Tentative Theoretical Analysis, 1962 (Box 47)
  - Rifkind, Robert S.: Woodrow Wilson and the Bolsheviks, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Resnick, Henry S.: Four Plays, vols. I and II, 1962 (Box 48)
  - Resnik, Michael D.: The Formalization of the Foundations of Geometry within the System of Symbolic Logic R., 1960 (Box 48)
  - Robinson, Armstead L.: In the Aftermath of Slavery: Blacks and Reconstruction in Memphis, 1865-1870, 1969 (Box 49)
  - Rizopoulos, Nicholas X.: Palmerston and the Pacifico Affair, 1958 (Box 49)
  - Roberts, Burgert: An Introduction to N.P. van Wyk Louw, 1962 (Box 49)
  - Ritterbush, Phillip C.: A Vision of Nature: The Poetry and Science of Erasmus Darwin, 1958 (Box 49)
  - Rigney, David B.: The World of Same Smiles, 1966 (Box 49)
  - Rutledge, A. Burt: The Interrelationships of Aristotle's Ethics, Politics, and De Anima, 1960 (Box 50)
  - Ryder, Stuart A.: The Sense of Nonsense, 1951 (Box 50)
  - Rolde, Neil R.: Seven Short Stories, 1953 (Box 50)
  - Rowell, Edward M.: Influences on Congress and Their Effect on Foreign Policy, 1953 (Box 50)
  - Rothman, James K.: Experimental and Theoretical Studies of Cell Membrane Structure, 1971 (Box 50)
  - Roberts, James Stone: Slides of Selected Drawings and Paintings, 1973 (Box 51)
  - Rubin, Martin H.: Sarah Gertrude Miller, 1971 (Box 51)
  - Shamos, Jeremy: The Self in Solitude, 1956 (Box 52)
  - Schaffer, David M.: Black Athens, 1970 (Box 52)
  - Sandback, Frederick L.: Project in Sculpture, 1966 (Box 52)
  - Sargous, Harry W.: Explanatory Material, 1970 (Box 52)
  - Salemme, F. Raymond: Studies on the Alkylation of Histidine in Rnase-S and the S-Peptide Component, 1967 (Box 52)
  - Schrom, David A., Jr.: The Pennsylvania Republican Party at Mid-Century, 1968 (Box 53)
  - Schiffrin, Andre: Leon Blum at the Riom Trial, 1957 (Box 53)
  - Schmetterer, Jack B.: The Seaway, the Pressure, and the Congress vols. 1 and II, 1952 (Box 53)
  - Showell, Philip S., Jr.: A Group of Short Stories, 1952 (Box 54)
  - Sherman, Thomas L.: National Medical Aid in Great Britain and the United States, 1962 (Box 54)
  - Sherman, Eric: Charles Lloyd--Journey Within, 1968 (Box 54)
  - Sheldon, Francis D.: Short Stories, 1950 (Box 54)
  - Selig, Edward I.: The Poetry of Thomas Carew: A Critical Study, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Schön, Donald: Poetry and Conduct, 1951 (Box 54)
  - Sinberg, Wlo L.: New Economic Policy in Russia--Another Blind Alley, 1955 (Box 55)
  - Simon, Harvey B.: The Pathway to Eternity, 1963 (Box 55)
  - Shufro, Edward G.: The Russo-Turkish War of 1828-1829, 1955 (Box 55)
  - Showalter, David W.: Plays and Short Stories, 1961 (Box 55)
  - Sonne, Christian R.: The Social and Political Views of A.S. Khomyakov, 1957 (Box 56)
  - Snavely, William G.: Entailment, 1962 (Box 56)
  - Smith, G. Gaddis: Coös, 1954 (Box 56)
  - Slavitt, David R.: Poem and Short Stories, 1956 (Box 56)
  - Smith, Jeffrey A.: The Age and Distribution of Ramapithecus, 1965 (Box 56)
  - Sinel, Allen S.: The Teaching of Communist Morality to Soviet Elementary School Children, 1946-1950, 1958 (Box 56)
  - Stapleton, Vaughan: Ideology and Social Change, 1961 (Box 57)
  - Stevenson, Charles: Two Studies for a Piece of Fiction, undated (Box 57)
  - Stark, Alexander: Peruvian Architecture in the XVI Century: the Huamangan Case, 1971 (Box 57)
  - Snell, Bradford: Metropolis in the Omni-Partisan Era, undated (Box 57)
  - Sullivan, Scott: Three Plays, 1958 (Box 58)
  - Startz, Richard: Microdata Analysis, undated (Box 58)
  - Stevens, Paul S.: Image and Intuition in the Poetic of T.E. Hulme, 1974 (Box 58)
  - Stridsberg, Albert B.: Giambattista Vico and the Modern World, vols. I and II, 1950 (Box 58)
  - Stimson, Hugh M.: Wang Wei, the Poet, 1953 (Box 58)
  - Shambroom, Donald: Hazardous Small Plants That Impress Our Women, vol. I, vol. II-Slides, 1973 (Box 59)
  - Savage, Samuel P.: The Metaphysics of Nihilism, 1968 (Box 59)
  - Thompson, Larry E.: To Make a Poet Black: A Study of the Harlem Renaissance, 1972 (Box 60)
  - Thompson, Josiah D., Jr.: The Moment of Presentness: An Analysis of Fear, Shame, and Guilt, 1957 (Box 60)
  - Thacher, Nicholas S.: A Far Other Butterfly, undated (Box 60)
  - Taub, Rebecca A.: Characterization of Wom--A Bacteriophaze of Pseudomas Putida, 1974 (Box 60)
  - Taylor, Council: Humanist Functions of Cultural Anthropology in America, 1950 (Box 60)
  - Talbott, Strobe: Fedor Tiutčev, Poet of Privacy, 1968 (Box 60)
  - Tolbert, Richard G.: Negro Nationalism, 1966 (Box 61)
  - Thompson, Chandler: Such Random Consolations, 1962 (Box 61)
  - Thom, Robert: Children of the Ladybug, 1951 (Box 61)
  - Templeton, J.M.: Title Unknown (seems to be about Uganda), undated (Box 61)
  - Tucker, Carll: Who from Their Labors Rest, 1973 (Box 62)
  - Tully, Robert E.: Patterns of Recognition, 1962 (Box 62)
  - Tuffli, Charles F., Jr.: The Inhibition of the Photosynthetic Rhythm of Acetabularia by Actinomycin D, 1965 (Box 62)
  - Ulian, Richard: Report on Two Israeli Farm Communes [author gave blanket permission to copy and quote but not to publish], 1950 (Box 63)
  - Vivian, James R.: Dennis Chavez, 1968 (Box 64)
  - Versenyi, Laszlo: The Thought of Martin Heidegger, undated (Box 64)
  - Villadsen, M. Kurt: The Novels of Ivy Compton-Burnett, 1954 (Box 64)
  - Watts, F. David: A Selection of Poems, 1972 (Box 65)
  - Wolff, Carl T.: The Tragic Spirit and the Modern Temper, 1953 (Box 65)
  - Warner, Eric D.: The Dauntless Master, 1974 (Box 65)
  - Williams, Douglas R.: The Symbolic World-View in the Matter, 1953 (Box 65)
  - Wong, Carey: Research and Written Work, 1972 (Box 65)
  - Weinmann, Robert L.: The Making of a Hero, 1957 (Box 65)
  - Wada W.: Portfolio of Photographs and Slides, 1971 (Box 65)
  - Wallace, John R.: The Formalization of a Meta-Language for Combinatory Logic, 1961 (Box 65)
  - Watt, Ward B.: Studies on the Pteridine Wing Pigments of the Butterfly Colias, 1962 (Box 65)
  - Weinstein, Allan: An Analysis of the Historical Background, Nature, and Religious Usage of Some Aspects of Medical Thought in the Midrash Rabbah, 1962 (Box 66)
  - Weinstein, Franklin B.: Revolt Within the New Deal, 1961 (Box 66)
  - Weiskel, Timothy C.: Education and Colonial Rule in French West Africa 1890-1945, 1969 (Box 66)
  - White, William L.: The Power of the Poor, 1967 (Box 67)
  - Weinberg, Robert L.: The Left Side of Paradise, 1953 (Box 67)
  - Werdell, Philip R.: The Forgotten Sumner: Icons of an Iconoclast, 1963 (Box 68)
  - Wilhelm, James J.: Goodbye to All This, 1954 (Box 68)
  - Walker, Geoffrey K.: The South Carolina Negro Seaman Acts, 1822-1845: Rehearsal for Secession, 1969 (Box 68)
  - White, William M., Jr.: The Colorado Fuel and Iron Corporation, 1961 (Box 68)
  - Wright, Donald: The Arms and Armour from Dura-Europos, 1963 (Box 69)
  - Wilhelm, John: see: Blum, Jake (Box 69)
  - Wilkinson, J. Harvie III: Harry Byrd and the Changing Face of Virginia Politics, 1967 (Box 69)
  - Woody, J. Melvin: An Inquiry into the Problem of Existential Communication, 1956 (Box 70)
  - Witty, Kenneth J.: A Call to Protest--Student Politics in Chile, 1963 (Box 70)
  - Yates, Douglas T., Jr.: John Lindsay and the New York Democracy, 1966 (Box 71)
  - Young, Robert M.: Problems of Transcendence, 1957 (Box 71)
  - Zelinsky, Paul: Slides of Paintings, 1974 (Box 72)
  - Correspondence of Chairman of the Scholar of the House Program; Project Proposals by Students, 1968-1970 (Box 72)
- Student essays and projects, circa 1963-1985; Accession 19ND-A-383
  - Mancusi-Ungaro, Harold R.: Michelangelo: the Bruges Madonna and the Piccolomini altar, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Charny, David: Modes of error in narrative fiction, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Ehle, Carolyn: Behavior and ecology of Brachyphylla cavernarum and Artibeus Jamaicensis (Chiroptera: Phyllostomatidae), 1977 (Box 1)
  - Hall, Judith E.: "Life for me ain't been no crystal stair." Representative black women in the United States 1825 to the present, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Moskwa, Alexander, Jr.: Aspects of Polish health care, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Powell, Amanda: Carrying voices: Spanish women poets, translations and original poems, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Schroeder, David Harry: Outline of my work as a Scholar of the House; and An historical and theoretical survey of twentieth century sound. With musical score, "Happy Birthday to You,'' and 9 audio tapes., 1977 (Box 3)